------------------OP-----------------------------
------------------ED-----------------------------
---------------------------------------------------------------------
あれ　いつもより人多くない？
今日から笹幡七夕祭りと言う
樱律联萌站 http://bbs.ylbud.com/
樱律联萌站为您带来高质量中日双语字幕
中日双语字幕由 樱律字幕组 制作
地元の祝祭が催されているらしい
感谢以下成员倾情制作
听译：五月、兔走之、吉禾　校对：深雪　时间轴：咲夜　后期：OMG
"Sasahata Tanabata Festival"
さって幡谷に到着したのはいいけど
Huh? Doesn't it seem
more crowded than usual?
どうも肝心なマグロナルドの方はお客が
I'm told today is the first
day of a local celebration
少なくて振るわないわね
called the Sasahata Tanabata Festival.
修羅場向きじゃないわ
Well, here we are in Hatagaya,
騒がしい店じゃないと
雰囲気が悪くなった時にも最悪だし
but the MgRonald's we came
to see is practically deserted.
それに相手の男に利があった場合は
"Sasahata Tanabata Festival"
職場環境乱すことにもなりかねない
This is no place for a proper fray!
We need a bustling restaurant,
or it'll suck when the mood sours...
そして上面や向きに目の前にはセンダッキがある
Plus if the man we're after has the advantage,
まずはあそこで作戦会議ね
理香　絶対楽しんでるよね
we might end up wrecking
the work environment...
And the perfect place is
standing right here! Sentucky!
We'll start with a council of war there!
Rika's totally enjoying this, isn't she?
この瞬間
在这瞬间
この場所がスダート
这里就是起点
イメージして見よう
试着想象一下
何ができるのかな
我能做些什么
Right here, this moment,
this is our starting point
信じられない出来事だってある
会发生些不可思议的事吧
Let's picture what we might be able to do
もっと超えて行けるね
克服一切走的更远
Unbelievable things can happen sometimes
ゼロから生まれるすべて輝いて
从零重生的一切都特别耀眼
More... we can push past this
FLYあの空へ
翱翔朝着那片天空
Everything is born from zero;
I want to shine, flap my wings hard
思い切り羽ばたきたい
想尽情地展翅
最高のスマイルで笑いながら
以最完美的笑容
さぁ、行く
笑着前行吧
And fly to that sky
未知の世界へと　今飛び出そうよ
奔向未知的世界仿佛就要飞出来
Come on, let's go, with
brilliant smiles on our faces!
未来を選び決めるのは自分
自己决定自己的未来
Let's fly off to an unknown world right now
夢を追いかけて行　こう泣く日をある
追逐着梦想前进　也会有哭泣的日子
それは大事な願い消えないで
珍贵的愿望不会消失
I decide, I'm the one who chooses my future
Let's follow our dreams
きっと会えるから
一定可以再次遇
Sure, some days we'll cry
明日の君
朝着未来的你
It's a precious wish, don't disappear
I'm going after the future you,
because I know I'll find you
"The Devil is a Part-Timer!"
The Hero Experiences a Fray
勇者、修羅場を経験する
First, you'll have to tell me
all about this "Maou" guy.
まずはその真奥って人について
詳しく聞かせてもらうわ
That might give us an idea
for how to settle your battle.
そこから修羅場解決の糸口が
見つかるかもしれないしね
Given he's the Devil and I'm a hero,
battle is all there's ever going to be.
私は勇者で
アイツが魔王である以上
修羅場しかないんだけどね
But who knows how this girl's going
to dodge Rika's misunderstanding...
でも
この子は理香の勘違いを
どう回避するつもりなんだか
An iced coffee for me. How about you two?
私、アイスコーヒーね
二人は
I suppose I'll have a
maple-biscuit-and-iced-tea set.
では、メープルビスケットとアイスティーのセットいただこう
Milk in the tea, please.
ミルクで頼む
Iced coffee.
アイスコーヒーで
I'll pay for all three of us.
あたしがまとまって払っておくからね
Oh, that'll be all.
以上で
Thank you, Miss.
かしこまりまいした
May I present you with
a Grand Opening coupon?
こちら　よろしければ
オープンフェアのクーポン券でございます
Thanks.
どうも
And now I shall lovingly prepare your order.
これより心をこめて調理いたします
麗しい女子に召し上がっていただけるとは
Surely the food will appreciate
being eaten by such lovely maidens.
商品もささ喜ぶでしょう
Here's your change, Miss.
こちら　お返しでございます
R-Right...
えっ
Here you go.
どうぞ
It's a crime that I've kept a lady waiting.
女性をお待たせするのは
罪なことをしてしまいました
ご注文の品どうぞお持ちくださいませ
Here is your order, Miss.
It's always men like that who turn
out to suck at the "casual" thing
ああいう男ほど意外と遊ぶの下手で
and just end up a pain in the neck.
面倒を抱え込むなよね
His sunglasses and cologne
are in poor taste, too.
サングラスも香水も趣味悪いし
What are you talking about?
何の話
Nothing, never mind.
ううん　何でもない　行こう 行こう
Let's go.
Now, then! My first question is,
how did things start?
さって　さって
まずはことの成り行きから伺いましょうか
His name is Sadao Maou, right?
Both of you give it to me straight!
真奥貞夫さんだっけ
ちゃんとあなた達の口から聞かせてもらおうか
To me, he's my neighbor
at my new boarding house.
私にとっては引越し先の隣人だ
I can say he's a good neighbor.
まぁ　良き隣人ではある
This girl!
この子
I want you to take down King Satan
with me, and then return to Ente Isla.
私と一緒に魔王サタンを倒し
エンテイスラに戻ってほしい
After that, now he's a "good neighbor"?
She's cool as a cucumber, I'll give her that.
とか言ってたくせに
良き隣人だなんて
まぁ　よしいけしゃあしゃあと
And you, Emi?
って　恵美は
Me, I'd happily kill him first chance I got.
私にとってはすぐにでも殺したい相手よ
Huh, conflicting opinions.
意見割りだね
But since you always put up a front, Emi...
ても　恵美って素直じゃないからな
Look, Rika, I'm going to be frank:
there's nothing between Maou and me.
ね　理香
はっきり言っておくけど
私はその真奥とはなんでもないの
I have totally different reasons for not
wanting him and Suzuno to be together,
鈴乃を引き合わせたくなかったのは
まったく違う理由で
so we are not fighting over him!
私達が真央を奪いあってるとはそんなじゃないのよ
This is what I mean about
you putting up a front.
だから
そういうところが素直じゃないんだって
Why are you so set on me and
Maou getting together, anyway?!
大体どうして私と真奥を
そんなにくっ付けたがるのよ
Just thinking about it is infuriating!
考えるのも忌々しい
That man is savage and cunning and
greedy and insensitive and poor and
あんな残虐で狡猾で意地汚くて
無神経で貧乏で
acts like you owe him for some random
umbrella and has no common sense!
拾った傘で人に恩着せるような非常識男
I cannot let that remark pass, Yusa!
聞き捨てならんぞ！   遊佐
Ashiya?! What are you doing here?
芦屋、何でここに
ずいぶん時間かかってるな
Ashiya's taking a really long time...
芦屋の奴
You want me to exhaustively consume
the fried chicken of this "Sentucky"?
私にセンダッキのフライドチキンになるものを
徹底的食してこいですと
Well, it's not really about the eating part...
いや、徹底的食べろうって言うか
If you wanted me to
exhaustively consume the offerings
（这里恶搞的是日本的著名超市连锁Life超市）
駅前のスーパーサイフ笹塚店のから揚げ
of the fried-food flash sale at
the SIFE supermarket by the station
タイムセール百グラム八十八円を
徹底的に食せというならばいざします
where I can get 100 grams for
88 yen, that would be one thing.
But Sire, our army does not
have the financial reserves
魔王様の当面の天敵となるセンダッキの
売り上げに貢献するような経済的余裕
to contribute to the sales of
your present nemesis, SFC!
わが軍にはございません
Would you just listen to me?
いいから、聞けよ
We're employing these methods
because it is a potential nemesis.
天敵と成り得るからこその手段だ
To win the battle,
we must first know our enemy.
勝負に勝つにはまず敵を知る
You can't tell me that you,
my top advisor, have forgotten that.
参謀のお前が忘れたとは言わせねぇぞ
Sire...
魔王様
I'm not telling you to just eat.
ただ食えってんじゃねぇ
I want you to eat, eat, eat
in an exhaustive investigation
食って食って食いまくて
敵の長所、弱点
of their strengths,
weaknesses, and everything else!
すべて徹底的に調べてこい
This is a necessary expense for my rise to power.
俺の出世にかかわる必要経費だ
I beg your aid.
頼む
If you feel that strongly,
Sire, I cannot refuse you.
そこまでおっしゃれるであれば
魔王様の意味背け訳にはまいりません
However!
ただし
I, Shiro Ashiya, will make my
thoroughgoing investigation
この芦屋四郎最小限の出費で
employing the minimum possible expenditure.
奴らを虱潰しに調べて参ります
Ashiya!
芦屋
Sire! Please leave this to me!
魔王様　　お任せください
Ashiya!
芦屋
- Ridiculous.
- Sire!
アホらしい
魔王様
Ashiya!
芦屋
I know I said "exhaustive,"
but he's taking too long!
徹底的にとは言ったが
時間かかりすぎだろう
Mr. Maou?
真奥さん
Oh, Chi, what's up?
どうした　ちーちゃん
I got a bunch of chores done...
とりあえず
いろいろな作業とか終わっちゃいましたけど
Hmm? Oh. Right, let's see...
そうか、そうだな
Everyone's spirits are down...
Well, I guess that's to be expected.
みんな　いつもの鍵が殺がれちまってるな
それも当然じゃ当然か
There's a huge crowd outside thanks
to the Sasahata Tanabata Festival,
外は笹幡七夕祭りのおかげて
大した賑わいだってのに
and yet look at this state of affairs...
the complete opposite of our enemy SFC.
天敵センダッキとは対象的に
店はこの状態だからな
どうする
What do I do? I can't just
keep twiddling my thumbs!
このまま手を拱いてるわけにはいかねぇぞ
Um, maybe we should stand outside
and invite people to eat here?
あの、お店の前で
お客さん　呼んだりした方はいいですね
客引き　それも手だが
Soliciting customers... It's a possibility,
but it might be better to wait and
devise countermeasures with Ashiya.
芦屋が来てから対策を立てた方はいいんじゃ
And more importantly,
the critical delivery isn't here yet,
それ以前に 肝心な物が来てないのに
どうやって客の手を引く
so how can we get the public's attention?
Should I make a move now?
But... no, I mustn't act now!
今、動かべきか
いや、しかし
今、動いても
I can't predict this battle at all!
読めん  まったく読めん
Who knew fighting on the front lines
of a major fast-food restaurant
大手ファストフード店の最前線の戦い
was so complex?!
ここまで奥義がするとは
You okay, Maa?
真君　大丈夫か
I know you're shift manager,
but don't shoulder everything yourself.
いくら時間帯責任者といっても
全部引き込まないでよ
That's right! I'm commander
of an army right now!
そうだ
今俺は一軍の将
If I show fear now, unrest
will spread among my men!
ここで動揺しては部下達に不安が広がる
Now is not the time to act!
今は動く時じゃない
Right now the tides are with them, that's all.
今はただ、相手に流れがあるのだけだ
But the tides are sure to turn!
We must wait for that moment!
しかし、必ずや俺達に流れが来る
それを待つんだ
And to prepare for when it comes...
そして流れが来たその時のために
窓を磨け
Polish the windows!
Roger!
ライット
- All that thought and that's your conclusion?!
- Please... come quick!
悩んだ最後それ？
頼む、早く来てくれ
What are you doing here?
Or actually, where were you hiding?!
何で貴方がこんなところにいるのよ
って言うか
今までどこにいったのよ
I noticed you come in,
but I wanted to avoid trouble.
貴様が入って来たのには気づいた
面倒事は避けたかった
But I cannot allow you to abuse the
master of my house in that manner.
しかし
わが家主をそこまで悪し様に罵る貴様を見逃しては
- It would stain my honor!
- Yeah, yeah.
私が廃る
はい      はい
Oh, hey, this is a perfect opportunity.
Ashiya, give me a hand here!
そうだ、芦屋
いい機会だから
力貸しなさい
It's a matter of your dignity and Maou's.
貴方や真奥の沽券に関わることよ
What? Why should I lend you a hand?
なに
何で私が貴様に力を貸さればならない
You've got to be here to
research this place, right?
どうせ　こっちのお店のリサーチにきたんでしょう
I'll treat you to whatever you want.
何でも好きなもの奢るわよ
Well, if you insist.
そこまで言うなら　仕方ないな
I didn't think you were that greedy.
あなたがそこまで意地汚いと　　予想外だわ
Don't get the wrong idea.
勘違いするの　今の私にとって
Right now, I must prioritize the
household budget above all else.
最優先させるべきもん　我が家の家計
For that, I shall bear any indignity;
I shall happily suffer any disgrace.
そのためにはどんな屈辱も耐え
喜んで自ら泥にまみれを
You sound like a fool.
普通にかっこう悪
At any rate, I was unable to
research salads and desserts
とにかく　デザートとサラダについては
予算オーバーでリサーチできなかった
due to budget constraints.
Later I shall order them.
後でそれを注文するとしようか
Um, I'm a little lost here... is he a friend?
えーと　なんだかよくわからないけど　お友達さん
- Absolutely not!
段ちで違うわ！
I don't know who you are, Miss,
どちら様かはご存知ませんが
but in terms of this group's relationships,
I am Miss Kamazuki's neighbor.
私はこの中の人間関係で言うならば
鎌月さんの隣人です　芦屋四郎と申します
My name is Shiro Ashiya.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Rika Suzuki, a coworker of Emi's.
あ、どうも　私は恵美の同僚の鈴木理香って言います
If you're Suzuno's neighbor,
does that mean you live with Mr. Maou?
すずのちゃんのお隣ってことは
真奥さんのお家ってこと
Yes. Do you know him, Miss?
そうですが　家の屋の主　ご存知で
I'm asking because
I want to know all about him.
よく知りたいから　よくお聞きしたいのよ
Know... all about him?
よく知りたい
Eh, it's not the sort of thing
you're worried about at all.
あ　あなたが警戒するようなことじゃまったくないわよ
Basically, this is about a man Emi
doesn't want other girls getting close to.
大まかに言うとね
恵美が女の子を近づけたくない男がいるって話しなんだけど
Yusa, what on Earth is she talking about?
遊佐　これはいったいなんの話だ
That's what I'd like to know, actually.
あたしはむしろ知りたいんだけど
A man Yusa doesn't want
other girls getting close to, eh?
遊佐が女の子を近づけたくない男は　ですか
And a matter of dignity?
沽券にかかわるか
This is what the phrase
"let the secret slip" means, Yusa.
語るの落ちるとはこのことだな
遊佐　　そうですね
Well...
I haven't told Miss Kamazuki this, either,
これは镰月にも初めてお話しますが
but Maou and I once ran a company together.
真奥と私はかつて　会社を経営していたんです
What?! A company?!
えっ　会社？
A-Ashiya?
あ　芦屋
What is he talking about?
何を言っているんだ　これは
Wait, you don't look much older
than we are... how old are you?
ていうか　私らと対して変わらないふうに見えるけど
いくつなの？
Our company mainly focused on
われわれの会社は主に土地運用や
real estate management
and personnel placement.
人材派遣に力を注いていました
We also dabbled in construction
and other industries occasionally.
また　建設業にも手を出したこともあります
Yes, we were called...
社名は　そう　   真奥組
"The Maou Syndicate"
...the Maou Syndicate!
Maou... Syndicate?
真奥組　何が人材派遣よ
"Personnel placement," my butt!
And Yusa...
そして遊佐は　ライバル社の社員でした
...worked for a rival company!
Emi, you worked in construction before?!
恵美　前の仕事　建設関係だったの
More like, how old are you again?!
ていうか　としいくつだっけ
いや　え　なんと言うか
Um, it's hard to explain...
If I recall correctly, weren't
you a temp at the time?
確かに　お前が当時派遣だったかな
A temp?!
I see, so the hero is a temp...
そっか　遊佐は派遣なのか
Don't take him seriously!
真に受けないでよ
Though we had our fingers in
many pies, we were still small enough
うちは手広くやっていたとはいえ
- that management had to
command the teams on-site.
- Bring those materials over here.
経営人が現場で陣頭指揮をとらなければならない程度の規模
- But Yusa was both skilled and
backed up by her company,
- Pleased to meet you. I'm Yusa.
ですが　遊佐は本人の優秀さと会社のバックアップを持って
- and she frequently vied
with us for our clients' jobs.
- ...and so this structure...
現場でよくわれわれと仕事の奪い合いをしていたのです
で、後はこの建築物は
- We were all so young, and all with much
the same level of business experience.
- I deeply apologize for the trouble!
われわれは全員が実務経験に大差もない若造でした
Japan was smack in the middle of the recession,
and with a major firm taking jobs from us,
当期は不況の真っ只中ですから
大手に仕事を奪われては
our company run by young upstarts
went down like a house of cards.
若層の経営する会社など簡単に消し飛んでしまいます
- And the final one to battle
us for an order was Yusa.
- Mr. Company President!
そして　最後に受注を争ったのは遊佐だったのです
- And the final one to battle
us for an order was Yusa.
- Thank you so much, Mr. Company President!
We lost, and the company went bankrupt.
われわれは負けて　会社は倒産
We drifted, eventually winding
up in a Sasazuka apartment,
流れ流れて笹塚のアパートに辿り着き
until almost a year later, we saw Yusa again!
一年近かくしてわれわれは偶然遊佐と再会しました
Takoyaki!
たこ焼き
I imagine Yusa had complex
feelings about her fallen competitors.
遊佐も過去の商売敵であるわれわれに
いろいろと思うことがあったのでしょう
She still checks in on us every now and again.
ときときわれわれの様子を見に来てくれるのですよ
Oh, I see.
ああ、そういう
However!
ただ真奥はまだ起業して成功する夢を諦めておりません
Maou has not given up on his dream
of starting a successful business!
Right now he is working
intensely at MgRonald's
今は一から経営というものを学ぶべく、マグロナルドで猛烈に働き
to learn all about
management from the ground up,
and in just one year has
been appointed shift manager.
一年で時間帯責任者応接窓になりました
As for me, I now play housewife all day long...
一方の私はと言えば　ひがれ一日中主婦業
How far I have fallen.
昔に比べ　情けない姿態です
Nonetheless! We intend to start
a business with our leader Maou again one day!
しかし　いずれわれわれは真奥のもとでもういち度起業を志す
I want to do everything
I can to support that dream!
私はそれを全力で支えたい
Still, entrepreneurship is a gamble.
ですが　起業とは謂わばギャンブル
I can understand why Yusa didn't want
Miss Kamazuki to grow too close to us,
そんなわれわれに　鎌月さんが巻き込まれたらと思えばこそ
out of fear that she'd get
dragged into that gamble.
遊佐が鎌月さんをわれわれと深く関わらせたくなかったのも
頷きます
- I'm plenty dragged in already.
- And Maou is what you might call stubborn...
そんなとっくに巻き込まれすぎたがなぁ
そして　真奥をしっかりといえば
He sees Yusa as an enemy,
and hates her on a fundamental level.
遊佐を敵と見なして　根本的には嫌っています
So I don't think the sort of thing you're
imagining would ever happen, Miss Suzuki.
ですから　鈴木が想像していらっしゃる
ようなことはないと思いますよ
Whoa, that sounds incredible...
when you guys are about my age...
や、なんか、すごいなあ　私と対して年変わらないのに
Now I'm embarrassed that I had such
a wild idea and blew it out of proportion
勝手にいろいろ妄想を膨らませて
首突っ込んだのが恥ずかしいわ
and butted into things.
And Emi, you should have told me!
恵美もそうならそうと　言ってくれればよかったのに
You wouldn't have listened, would you?
言っても聞かなかったでしょう
My family runs a small factory,
and when times really got rough,
私も実家が小さな工場で本当に危ない時なんか
we pulled through it by all working together.
みんなで協力して乗り切ったからさ
You said you'd "fallen," but your Mr. Maou
情けないなんて言っただけど
eats the meals you've made,
sleeps on the futon you've aired out,
その真奥さんだって あなたが作ったご飯食べて
あなたが干した布団で寝て、
and wears the underwear you've washed, right?
あなたが洗ったパンツはいているんでしょう
ほー、はー
Yes...
Then you're everyone's firm foundation,
so I think you should be prouder of yourself.
なら、あなたがみんなの基礎を支えているんだから
もっと誇っていいと思う
Since you're supportive of each other
like that, I know things will go well!
あなたたちはそうやってお互いに支え合っている間なんだから
きっとうまく行くわよ
You're the first person
who's ever said that to me.
そんなこと言ってくださったのは、あなたが初めてです
Thank you for encouraging me...
I feel a bit stronger for it.
励ましてくださて、すこし元気がでました
あ
- Rika?
- Huh?! What?!
理香
あ！何？何？
Uh, I'm kind of asking you that.
What's gotten into you?
や、こっちが何いいなんだけど　　どうしたの突然
It's nothing, it's nothing,
it's nothing, it's nothing!
何でもない　何でもない　何でもない　何でもない
She said that four times.
四回も言った
But wow, everybody's got a past, huh?
でもそっか　　人に歴史ありね
Anyway, this clears up
the misunderstanding, right?
とにかく、これで誤解も解けたでしょう　そろそろ帰ろう
Let's go home...
Now I'm personally interested
in checking out this "Maou" guy!
なんか　個人的にその真奥って人見たくなった
Huh?!
はー
For one thing, if he's so gifted, I should
invest in making the connection now!
その真奥って人が逸材なら　将来のために繋がり作るべきだしね
Hold it, what are you talking about?
ちょっと何言ってるの
Mr. Ashiya, you need to report
to him about the enemy, right?
芦屋さんも　敵情報告があるんでしょう
- So why don't we all go together?
- Whoa, Rika!
なら　みんなでいかない？
で、理香！
You're coming too, of course?
当然、貴様も来るなぁ
Now get me one of those maple biscuits
とりあえず そのメープビスケットと
and a salad with Thousand
Island dressing, takeout.
あとはサラダオフサウザンドドレッ
シングをテークアウトしてもらおうか
- Hey... Wait...
- Miss Kamazuki, I must thank
you for your constant help.
えっ　ちょっ
鎌月さんには日ごろのお礼もあります　私はご馳走しますので
Allow me to treat you.
あ、なんで、こうなるな
Why did things turn out like this?
ああ、どうどん最悪の展開になっていってるわ　これ
The situation is getting worse and worse.
Oh my, Miss.
おやおや お嬢さん、そんな悩ましげな顔をしていては
If you allow things to trouble you so,
you won't be able to enjoy your food.
せっかくの食事がおいしくなくなってしまいますよ
Uh, thanks, I guess.
それはどうも
No matter how much one worries,
どんなに思い悩もうが　時間というのは否応なしに
状況を変化させていきます
over time things change
whether we like it or not.
I hope you won't regret it when the situation
becomes totally out of your control.
自分の意志を介在させることができなくなったとき
後悔されませんように
This is the first time I've been given
advice on life by an SFC employee.
センダッキの店員さんにそんな
お節介をやかれたのは初めてだわ
Oh, I'm sorry for being presumptuous.
これは　差し出がましいことと申しました
But please let me tell you just one thing.
ですが　これだけは言わせてください
Men take advantage of women
when they're vulnerable.
男は女性が弱ったところに付け込むものです
Please be on your guard at all times.
夢々お気をつけなさい
What do you mean by that?
どういう意味
Well, nothing really.
いえ　特に深い意味はありませんよ
Thank you very much. Please come see us again.
ありがとうございました　またのお越しをお待ちしております
They're giving out Grand Opening coupons, eh?
オープンニングセールクーポンか
Furthermore, I tried their food, too.
さらに試してみったところ　看板商品であるフライトチキンが
Their trademark product,
fried chicken, is amazing!
Depending on the part of the chicken,
you can even eat the bones!
部位によりますが骨まで食べられる驚きもの
Even bones?!
骨までって　ていうか　普通骨食わなくねぇか
Wait. People don't normally eat bones.
And that's not all.
They evidently serve organic coffee.
さらにさらに　コーヒーはオーガニックコーヒーを採用しているとか
Coffee made from ogres?!
オーガニックのコーヒーだと？！
"Organic." It means
"grown with natural pesticides."
オーガニック有機栽培のことです
Naturally pestilent ogres, eh?
なるほど　有機を出してオーガか
But besides those things, I don't
think there's an extreme difference.
しかし、これ以外は極端に差があると思いません
Their customer service was quite normal, too.
接客もごく普通でした
The only reason I can think of at this point is
that passersby are just drawn to new things.
後は通りかかる人が新しいものに目移りしいるとしか
I see.
そっか
In any case, we'll at least try putting up a fight.
とにかに　こっちも悪あがきやってみるわ　ご苦労だったなぁ
Thanks for your help.
もったいない言葉　私もささやかではありますが
I hardly deserve those words.
Although it's not much,
I'll contribute to your sales, Sire.
ここは真奥様の売り上げに貢献させていただきます
Two Big Mag burger sets with
large drinks and fries, please.
ビッグマグロバーガーセット二つ、
ドリンクもポテトもLサイズでお願いします
Urushihara will probably complain,
but this'll be our dinner tonight.
漆原は文句を言うでようが、今日の夕食はこれでいきます
If he complains about the food, give him
a good beating. I'll give you permission.
飯に文句いうようなら　俺が許可するから　ぶん殴れ
- As you wish, Sire.
- Ah-choo!
御意
In addition... please expect
great things from those girls.
それに　彼女たちには期待してください
Okay... though I don't know what you mean.
あ、なんかよくわからんか
Well then, I pray for your success in battle.
では、ご運をお祈りしております
Wow, they seem really tight.
On top of that, he acts totally professional.
えい、彼らの繋がり相当なもんね
それに　すごいプロ根性
You're surrounded by capable people, Emi.
エミの周り　できる人多いね
Oh, can I count myself among them?
あっ あたし自身もカウントしていい？
Knock yourself out.
まあ　ご自由にどうぞ
Their chairs are harder than the ones at SFC...
センダッキよりすごく堅い
Excuse me, M-i-s-s-e-s...
あのう　お、客、様～
What?
何よ
Could you sit down after
you've placed your order?
お席にはご注文されてからかけていただけませんかね
ああ
Then bring me a small iced coffee.
じゃ　アイスコーヒーSサイズ一つ
持ってきて
Our restaurant is self-service. We'd like
our customers to order at the register.
当店レジ注文のセルフサービス何ですよね 基本的に
Fine, I'll order an apple pie too, so show
some gratitude and bring it to the table.
じゃあついでにアップルパイまた頼んであげるから
ありがたく持ってきなさい
- Miss...
- You're the Mr. Maou, aren't you?
お客様
あなたが真奥さんでしょう
You somehow aren't as
charismatic as I thought you'd be.
なんか思ってたあと
カリスマ性ないね
Your restaurant is empty
when you're in charge, too.
責任を持った時間帯に店すいてるし
What're you saying out of nowhere?
Who do you think you are?!
草間はやむから棒に
一体何様だお前！
Hey, that's not very polite!
ちょっと 言葉遣いなってないじゃない
You want me to send a letter to your headquarters
telling them that you've got an attitude?
態度悪い店員って本社に投書しちゃうよ
Shut up! Restaurants have rules
that even customers need to follow.
うっせい
客にだって従ってもらわなきゃなら
ねぇ店のルールってもんがあるんだ
Besides, who the heck are you?!
大体あんたなんなんだよ
I'm Rika Suzuki. I'm Emi's coworker.
私鈴木理香　エミの同僚よ
Mr. Sadao Maou. These two and
Mr. Ashiya told me about you.
真奥貞夫さん　貴方のことは
この二人や芦屋さんから聞いたわ
Ashiya did? When? What did he tell you?
芦屋のやつが？
いつ？何を話したって
Ah-choo!
Well, Mr. Ashiya and Emi's
opinions of you were totally one-sided,
まあ芦屋さんとエミは
かなりワンサイトのものの見方だったから
so I came to check you out myself.
あたしは直々に確かめに来たのよ
I don't get what you're saying,
but are you one of those busybody types?
何言ってるかわかんねーな
あんたあれか？
おせっかいな人か？
あ　ったく
Seriously, first there's no
customers and then Emi shows up...
客は来ないし エミは来るし
You shouldn't talk like that, Mr. Maou!
だめですよ真奥さん
そんなこといっちゃ
Miss Yusa is also a valuable customer.
遊佐さんも大切なお客さんですよ
はい　アイスコーヒーとアップルパイは出来立てです
Here you go! Iced coffee and
an apple pie fresh from the oven!
Sorry, Chiho. I just got
carried away because of Maou...
ごめんね千穂ちゃん
なんか真奥は相手だから　つい
Don't worry about it. I know.
大丈夫です
分かってますよ
Good Chiho, you seem to be working hard.
千穂殿　精が出るようだ
Hi, Miss Suzuno!
こんにちは　鈴乃さん
Are you Miss Yusa's friend?
お客様は遊佐さんのお友達ですか？
That's right. I'm Emi's coworker. I'm Rika Suzuki.
そうよ　エミの同僚　鈴木梨香
I'm Chiho Sasaki.
私　佐々木千穂といいます
Miss Yusa has been very nice to me.
遊佐さんにはいろいろお世話になってます
How cute...
可愛い＝ｖ＝
Excuse me?
はい？
How cute! What's with this girl?! She's so cute!
可愛い！何この子可愛いんだけど！！
Hey, what're you doing?!
ちょっと何やってんのよ
Isn't it unfair how many gifted
people you have around you, Emi?!
エミの回りの人間で逸材多すぎない
She's polite and has good work ethics.
礼儀正しくて
仕事に哲学あって
On top of that, she's cute!
That's cheating! Cheating I tell you!
おまけに可愛くて
犯則よ犯則
Hey, what are you, a drunk
old man? Stop it, Rika!
酔っ払いの親父じゃないんだから 理香
Okay, okay.
はいはい　ごめんね 千穂ちゃん
Sorry, Chiho. I just got so excited.
お姉さんつい興奮しちゃって
O-Okay, though I don't
know what this is about...
あっはい　なんかよく分かりませんけど
So what're you gonna do now?
で　あんたはこれからどうすんの？
Huh?
あ？
You told Mr. Ashiya that you'd
try putting up a fight or something.
芦屋さんに悪あがきしてやろうのこと
いってたんじゃない
This is a good chance, so I'll just say it
straight... I want to see how you work.
この際はっきりいうけど
あたしはあなたの仕事ぶりを見たいのよ
What the heck is your deal?
一体なんなんだあんた
Mr. Ashiya... Chiho...
あの芦屋さんといい
千穂ちゃんといい
There are many gifted people around Emi.
エミの回りには逸材が揃ってるんだから
So I'm guessing that you aren't
the idiot that you appear to be.
あんたも見た目どおりのボンクラではないと睨んでるだけど
In short, you're trying to
say that I look like an idiot?
つまりそれは俺の見た目は盆暗だといいたいのか
It might be more than just looks.
ひょっとしたら中身もかも
Fine!
上等だ
The hell with SFC's coupons!
センダッキーのクーポンがなんだ
We'll compete by using flyers!
こっちは散らしで対応する
How about some MgRonald's burgers?!
マグロナルドのハンバーガーどうですか？
Please stop by!
どうぞいらっしゃいませ
- It's no use!
- What?!
だめです
何を？！
Then, we'll advertise that our products
don't have bones and are easy to eat!
それならこっちは骨がなくて食べやすいことを
アピールするんだ
How about a Big Mag burger?!
They don't have bones and are easy to eat!
ビッグマグロバーガーはいかがですか
骨がなくて食べやすいですよ
Isn't it just natural that
burgers don't have bones?
ハンバーガーに骨がないってそりゃ当たり前じゃない
You say some silly stuff!
面白いこという子だね
You're cute!
っすがかわいい！！（OvO）
It's no use.
だめです
Yeah, I guess...
だよな
Kawa-cchi! Now that it's come
to this, isn't it time for us to begin
川口　こうなったら
商品買わない人でも自由にトイレ使わせてあげる
Operation Let People Use the Restroom
Even if They Don't Buy Anything?!
作戦できるべきじゃネイ
What's the point of that?!
それなんのいみあんの？
How pathetic...
だめだこりゃ。。
Is Maou in?
真奥ちゃんいるかい？
Mr. Nabe! I've been waiting for you!
渡辺さん　待ってましたよ
It's a request from you, of course
I'd come! Sorry I'm a little late.
そりゃあ真奥ちゃんの頼みだし
っえちょっと遅くなってすまなかったな
No problem! You're a life-saver!
全然いいっすよ　助かりました
It'll be my treat, so please have something!
俺おごりますから
何か食べてくださいよ
Now that I've delivered what
you asked for, I'll go home.
届けるもん届けだし
My wife's making dinner for me, so...
Thanks for your offer, though.
上さんがそば麺引き作ってるから
気持ちだけいただくよ
I'll see you on the next cleaning day.
Say hello to Miss Kisaki.
また　次の清掃でな
木崎ちゃんによろしく
Amazing! He gave us really nice ones!
スーゲー　立派なもんもらいましたね
Let's hurry up and decorate
before the dinner rush starts!
ディナーのピーク前にささっと飾り付けちゃうよ
やりましょうやりましょう
Yeah, let's do it!
Maa, here you go!
真奥君　もって来たよ
Do you think we have enough ornaments?
飾り　これだけで足りますかよね
Okay, let's use the flyers.
よーし　チラシを使おう
Is it okay to use them to make ornaments?
いいの？　飾りに使っちゃったり
I'm the current shift manager.
I'll give you permission!
時間帯責任者の俺は許可する
What's going on?
何なの？
The Sasahata Tanabata Festival
gave Mr. Maou the idea.
真奥さんが笹幡七夕祭りにあわせて
He thought we'd have customers
write their wishes on strips of paper
短冊にお願いを書いて
七夕飾りをお客さんにしてもらおうって考えたんです
and decorate the trees using them.
He asked the manager to get
permission from our regional office
飾りつけをしてくれたお客さんにはドリングのSサイズ
をサービスするっていう許可を管轄事務所に申請してもらうよう
to give a complimentary small drink
to the customers who participated.
店長に提案してたんです
He then asked that old man who came
by earlier, Mr. Watanabe, for the trees.
それで　真奥さんが地域の定期清掃ボランティアで
知り合った渡辺さんっていうさっきのおじいさんの家に
Mr. Maou got to know him while
volunteering for neighborhood cleanup,
生えてる笹をわけて貰うようと願いしてたんですよ
and learned that he grows
bamboo trees in his yard.
Maou... volunteers for
neighborhood cleanup?
真奥が
地域清掃のボランティア
Of course, we don't know if
this will directly affect our sales,
もちろん　直接結果につながるか分かりませんけど
but the mood in the restaurant
has changed a bit, right?
それでも少しは
お店の雰囲気変わりましたよね
- All right!
- Whoa!
Good!
He is pretty good.
できるやつじゃん
I'll admit that he's a hard worker.
仕事熱心であることは認めるわ
Oh?
あれ？
How pretty!
きれい
Is this the MgRonald's with that
cute girl who says silly things?
可愛い娘が面白いこと言ってる　つってここ？
I saw her pic in a tweet!
何ですか？
What is it?!
Mom, I wanna write my wish and decorate it!
ママ
短冊飾りたい
What?! Seriously?!
ええ　マジ？
They just put bamboo trees out and
now this? What kind of feng shui is it?
笹立てただけで
こんなにってどんな風水
I can't believe it!
信じらんないだけど
All right, guys! Take up battle positions!
よし！
総員戦闘拝辞につき
It's time for war!
軍だ　軍立
Yeah!
お～～す！
Welcome! Welcome!
いらっしゃいませ！　いらっしゃいませ！
Once you've decided on
your order, please get in line!
ご注文お決まりのかたがた
一列にお並びください
Welcome! The seats over there are not taken.
いらっしゃいませ
あちらのお席が空いていますので　どうぞ
Okay. I'll show you the way.
はい
分かりました　ご案内致しませ
一二三四
Where will morning start from, in this quiet sky?
どこから朝になる
从何处开始是清晨
静かな空
安静的天空
Fingertips twining in a pinky
swear I pretended not to see
見ないふりをした指きり
装作没看见的拉钩
恋日の先笑われた
恋爱之前被嘲笑
If the moon's been laughed at,
she'll sink away toward yesterday
つきなら  消えてゆくんだ
就算是月亮 也会要消失
昨日の方角
向着昨天的方向
Liar, coward... if I'm all these things at once
うそつき　臆病者
胆小的人　说谎精
みんなまとめて　  僕なら　最低言ったのは
大家总结的这些　　我的话   就说声差劲
Then I only blossomed in dreams
夢の中だ
在梦中
I hid in the moon's shadow,
but the truth is, I was crying
月の影に隠してた
藏在月影中
本当はね　泣いていだ
其实正在哭泣
The tears won't flow anymore...
did they all dry up?
涙はもう流れない
眼泪已经不再流
枯れてしまうたな
枯竭了吧
If I could forgive everything,
maybe they'd flow again
何もかも許せたら
虽然什么都原谅的话
流れるかもしれないけど
眼泪可能还是会流出来
But these are all things I want to protect
守りたいものばかりだなあ
全都是想要守护的东西
The Devil and the Hero Take
a Break from the Daily Routine